Dmitry Belyaev

Front-End Developer

blv.dmitry@gmail.com

Summary

https://bananabobby.github.io

First and foremost, I pay attention to the quality of products I develop and push myself to reach out the best possible results. However never underestimate the value of business goals and project deadlines.

Second of all, I am fully a team player and believe in trustworthy team mindset that eventually leads to healthier decisions. Still am experienced self-maintained front-end developer.

In addition absolutely appreciate qualitative and clean design and believe it's not about following trends but rather understanding issues your service should solve to make the metrics increase.

Experience

Senior Frontend Developer at Superjob.ru

April 2017 - Present

Has been employed as a front-end developer for working on mobile version update.

Leveled up to a senior front-end developer.

Currently working on UI kit development based on material design using React/Redux and its related libraries.

Frontend Developer at Mail.Ru Group

September 2012 - April 2017 (4 years 8 months)

Started as an html/css developer working on 12 media projects.

Leveled up to a lead front-end developer position at Kino/Auto projects team consisting of 3 front-end developers.

- Created UI kit (Fest, Stylus, Javascript, jQuery) with shared codebase for desktop and mobile platforms which is used on all of the media projects in company. Had been one of its leading maintainers.
- Developed and successfully launched mobile versions of all projects within a year.
- Worked on redesigning of desktop versions in 3 different projects.

- Launched a bunch of special projects. In particular, the most successful ones were highlighted in social media, tech news portals.
- Contributed to our handmade ¡Query based Javascript framework
- Had been signed for a role of a team lead which counted 3 front-end developers. In addition was responsible for tasks planning for weekly sprints with PM and further discussion of API with backend team.

Frontend Developer

April 2016 - January 2017 (10 months)

Worked on a prototype of a flight search web application. Team counted just 3 people, so I was the only developer in the team.

- Built a prototype of the service (React, Redux, Webpack, Stylus).
- Made an Express API for fetching SkyScanner search results.

Html / Css Developer

April 2011 - August 2012 (1 year 5 months)

- Released more than a thousand handmade html/css pages with unique designs.
- Developed a "bootstrap" for time optimization which resulted to 2x faster development.

Html / Css Developer

October 2010 - January 2011 (4 months)

- Took part in development of the ygo.ru website.
- Developed two online clothing shops.

Education

Moscow Institute of Electronics and Mathematics (Technical University)

Master's degree, 2007 - 2012

Dmitry Belyaev

Front-End Developer

blv.dmitry@gmail.com



Contact Dmitry on LinkedIn